FROM ME TO YOU: KIMI NI TODOKE
3RD SEASON
The class trip
was a whole lot of fun.
And the biggest event of our second year
of high school... is over.
Man, those pineapples
were so good!
So the second day,
we went to the aquarium, had pineapples,
went to Cape Manzamo...
And was that it?
Oh, and then we had
a little bit of free time that night.
I remember, 'cause you and Mogi-cchi...
What's wrong?
It's, uh... how do I say it?
That sure was fast, eh?
It's fine.
There's nothing I coulda done.
And it'd be a pain
to have you both tiptoe around me.
Besides, looking back on it now,
he wasn't my type at all. The end.
P-- pretty sure
you're actually pissed.
- Uh...
- Hmm?
...was this Ryukyu Village?
Let me see.
Oh wow! Look at that face!
This was right after she got confronted
by that girl from Class--
Argh!
You didn't have to rip it up like that!
C'mon! The look on your face
was pure gold!
I did. I don't need the reminder.
Okay, but you weren't
the only one in the picture, you know!
Yeah, you're right.
Sawako was in that one too. Sorry.
- Oh...
- Wha--
Oh, look, I ripped through Ryu.
Speaking of, how have things been
between you two?
Uh. Normal.
We talk and hang at his place...
So pretty much the same as before.
Oh, that's right.
His birthday's coming up next month.
Gift, huh?
If you ask me, you might as well
just start dating already.
What?!
I mean, it really makes no difference
whether you two are going out or not.
It's still you and Ryu.
Huh?! You could not be more off base!
You don't get it, do you, Yano-chin?
I mean, if we started dating,
that would mean
k-- kissing and stuff like that!
Hmm?
- Did you...?
- No. We definitely haven't. Seriously!
So, I don't get it,
what's wrong with you and Ryu kissing?
- Everything!
- Huh? You totally could.
Not in a million years!
It's just that...
I've never seen him that way. Ever.
What if we dated and broke up?
- I don't wanna think about it.
- 'Kay, then don't break up.
Who's the one
who broke up with Mogi right away?
It's never even crossed my mind.
And I just don't want to change
what we have going for us now.
Anyway.
I was in love with Toru, remember?
After our big class trip ended,
a lot of things were
a little different than they were before.
First, Ayane decided
not to go out with Mogi anymore.
- Hey, Chizuru?
- Hmm?
Here. Pin says you need to bring this
back to him after school. Redone.
Then Chizu decided she wasn't
going to go out with Sanada after all.
What is it?
It's my career questionnaire.
Wow! What a moron!
It's just that I haven't decided!
As for me...
- Uh, hey, Kazehaya.
- Hmm?
I've got a present for you.
Uh? A picture? For me?
Thanks!
It's of Sawako in her undies.
Oh, please.
I'm obviously kidding, you dork!
- Sorry to rain on your parade.
- Wha--
- You can have it though.
- I don't want it!
Oh, it's me.
It's not like
I don't want any photos of you, Kuronuma.
Man, your boyfriend sure is awful, huh?
This has nothing
to do with you! I'll take it!
I'll take it.
Thanks for this.
Sawako and Kazehaya
are the same as ever, huh?
Uh-huh.
Uh--
On my end, Kazehaya and I
aren't chatting quite as much.
And I could just be imagining things,
but he also... doesn't seem to look my way
all that often.
Needless to say, he doesn't hold my hand.
It feels like there's
a little more distance between us now.
Sawa... ko.
Sh-- Shota.
Hey. Close your eyes.
The days...
...are getting shorter, huh?
Uh... mmm.
Wait, am I expecting more than I should?!
Like holding hands,
using our first names,
closing some of the distance between us?
Were those things,
like the summer and Okinawa... fleeting?
Like a mirage that we saw
because of the season's heat,
too exhilarating to last?
Summer is over, and fall will pass soon.
Then the second winter since I met
everyone will be right around the corner.
EPISODE 3
GIRLFRIEND AND BOYFRIEND
- Oh, you're Ayane, right?
- Uh, who are...
Oh! Kento Girls, right?
- She called us Kento Girls!
- What does she mean by that?
Hey, in Okinawa, you were hanging out
and chatting with Kento for a bit, right?
- You mean on the free day, or...
- Yeah, exactly.
I remember it was when we were
all chilling with Kento and Tsuru, right?
What is this?
The thing they did to Chizu?
Are they feeling me out?
So, Ayane.
Can we ask if you like Kento?
Yep, here it comes.
No, but I don't dislike him either.
Oh, really?!
Huh?
You see, we heard
you went through a breakup.
- Mm-hmm.
- That must've been rough.
Actually, I recently broke up
with my boyfriend too.
What?!
Who told you about that? Kento?
No. Just rumors.
Kento never gossips
about that stuff.
Right? He's an ally to all girls.
Uh, so, is it that
all of you like Kento, then?
And then you're also all friends?
I don't understand how that can work.
What?!
I mean, we all just adore Kento
because he's so genuinely kind.
Like, back when I got dumped
by my boyfriend,
Kento went through it with me
and let me vent as much as I needed to.
For me, it was when
I wasn't getting along with mine.
My boyfriend actually goes
to another school,
but Kento gives me all kinds of advice.
It's really nice to have
a boy around like that.
I love having girlfriends too,
but boys just fill a different
kind of space, ya know?
Since we always hang out
as a group, it's not cheating. It's fun.
It makes us feel so much better.
So...
...if you're up for it,
you should join us sometime,
so we can have a good time together.
It'll be fun! It'll be fun!
- It'll be... fun?
-   It'll be fun!
Close call! If I'm not careful,
I'll end up becoming a Kento Girl!
Oh no, I think I'll be fine
on my own for now, but thanks!
Ahh!
- But, hey...
- Hmm?
Don't any of you
ever get any romantic feelings for Kento?
You must have at least thought about
going out with him or something.
Hmm. Well, let me think about it.
- I wouldn't mind that, but...
- It's true that we all love him a lot,
and flipping the switch from platonic
to not wouldn't be very hard, but...
there's not another person
that could fill that role, so...
Then, what if Kento found someone?
Like a girlfriend?!
Yeah, that's true.
'Cause he's single now, isn't he?
There was a time
when he was dating someone, right?
Yeah, and it was more than just once too.
Oh, so in other words...
That wouldn't really
change anything for us, probably.
Hmm.
There's no replacing Kento, huh?
I had no idea, but I guess
Kento's actually pretty widely loved.
Please.
Hm.
Oh.
Oh, I guess that's his train.
Ayane.
The hell?!
I thought you were long gone by now!
Stay away from me!
Ouch! That stings. But at least
I know you're the same old Ayane.
I'm glad I stayed here.
So, you've been avoiding me, haven't you?
Hm.
I was embarrassed, so yeah.
Don't act surprised!
You've been totally watching me
since all that happened.
Anyway, it's not like
I normally cry that much or anything.
It's just...
Uh, but don't get me wrong,
that doesn't mean I was taking it
particularly hard either, so...
Here. It's a warm one.
Thank you.
No prob.
I see.
So this is how someone
gets turned into a Kento Girl.
Right now, I think I get how they feel.
I mean, he's not a bad guy.
He's actually gentle and kind.
Do you know why
I'm always watching you, Ayane?
The train on Platform 2
will be departing soon.
Please watch your step.
Chizu!
Here are those sushi rolls!
Take them over to Ryu's, will ya?
Oh. Mm-hmm.
Huh?
Hold on a second, Yoshida rejected you?
Uh-huh. Didn't I tell you?
No. I-- it's fine, but...
are you two okay after that?
Yeah, I mean, I knew that Chizuru
would react that way right off the bat.
So, in a way, I feel relieved.
Since that person
was always you.
Always?
Always, since when?
Always...
Honestly, I'm glad that
it came down to this.
'Cause now you can move on
and have your own life.
That time too?
You really did love him.
I know you did.
Then too?!
Always?
I do go over to his place if I have to.
And we talk... if we need to.
Normal, huh?
You're acting way more normal, Ryu.
Is this what normal is for us from now on?
I need ya to level up for me!
What are you doing in my room
before I even got home?
C'mon, Ryu, you know the deal.
What's yours is mine.
No way. Nope!
I can't talk about
those silly things with him.
Not anymore.
Is that how it's gonna be between us?
From now until forever?
To be honest, I'm confused.
I can't make heads or tails of it.
Could it be that this
was all just some sort of dream?
Hmm?
If you're looking for Ryu, he's upstairs.
- I was just leav--
- He say anything?
Here! Give this to him!
- Huh?
- They're sushi rolls, 'kay?
Wha--
W-- wait, Yoshida!
I could always tell Ryu anything.
I assumed we'd always be together.
Always... but...
If you don't actually
have feelings for Sanada,
you shouldn't hang around
with him so much.
But thinking that...
was stupid.
This really isn't a dream.
It's over, isn't it?
The "always" I thought we had.
Yoshida told me to give this to you.
Sushi rolls.
She also asked if you said anything to me.
I assume she meant about your confession.
Sorry. I didn't think.
I said you did.
I don't expect you
to lie for me, Shota.
These are frickin' great.
- Does she bring sushi to you often?
- Yeah.
Since third grade.
Chizuru, is she doin' okay?
Well, she kinda ran off.
Hi, Ryu!
Oh... hi.
Thanks for the food last night.
Of course!
Anyway, would you mind bringing this bag
to Chizu for me?
She completely forgot about it.
Oh. That's not like her.
I was surprised too.
She was gone by the time I noticed.
And she'd even left her rice balls behind.
She left her rice balls?
So the only absence is Yoshida, huh?
That brat.
And she never resubmitted
her career questionnaire.
Better not be flakin' on me.
Does she have a cold?
Hey. Is that Chizu's bag?
Well...
I see.
It's perfectly normal for Sanada
to have something of Chizu's with him.
Those two...
really are back to normal, then?
He confessed his feelings,
she rejected him,
but it's like nothing's changed.
But is that actually possible?
Wouldn't that be too much
to handle emotionally?
It's beyond what I can imagine.
But maybe those two
have a different kind of special bond.
And that's why
they can be totally okay like this?
It sure is unusual
for Chizu to be absent like this.
Mmm, do you think she might be sick?
- Wanna stop by on our way home?
- Mm-hmm.
In the meantime,
I'll text her just in case.
Sure is lonely
without Chizu today, huh?
Do you know why
I'm always watching you... Ayane?
What do you want?!
- You don't need to be so wary of me.
- I'm not!
You're just taking it
that way, that's all!
Anyway, I came over here
because I'd like to talk to Sadako.
Oh.
Great!
Then, why don't you two get to talking?
I'll be in the bathroom, see ya!
Is that cool?
If I go talk to Sadako alone?
Oh, that's right.
That's how it works now, huh?
You don't need
my permission, Kuronuma,
You're allowed to talk
to whoever you want to.
You're a person, not a thing.
Uh, right.
Don't worry!
It's not like I'm gonna do
anything weird to her, okay?
- You're right about that!
- Let's go, Sadako.
Being more aware
of how other people feel
means you carry a lot more
of that emotional weight with you, right?
- Huh?
- That's how it must be for Ayane.
Ah, but there was something else
that I wanted to bring up with you.
I've noticed things seem a little strained
between you and Kazehaya.
So things
really are tense between us, then?
I was hoping it was just me
misreading things again!
I'm sorry.
I figured you must have noticed already.
You're good about that.
Usually, people say that I'm dense.
That's just because you don't
notice things about yourself though.
I wouldn't say dense.
You clearly have a lot on your mind,
so it's easy to miss stuff.
You think?
When you assume something
is just your imagination, the truth is,
a solid 95% of it is most likely true.
Whoa! So 95%!
Yeah, that works for me!
Though from what I picked up
when we were talking,
Kazehaya didn't sound all that confident.
Either way, there's no question
he's totally crazy about you.
When we first met, I used to think that
you and Kazehaya lived in completely
different worlds from each other.
But that's not the case at all.
I think you're right next to each other.
In fact, I don't think
you could be much closer.
But... when you're not facing each other,
you're looking as far off
into the distance as you can.
So, yeah, things may be a little weird
between you at the moment,
but if you close your eyes
and wait for five seconds, well,
I'd bet anything
things will get sorted out. Yeah?
I-- I've heard that
somewhere before!
Remember, you need to close your eyes
and count to five.
- Oh, no, thank you!
- So what's the problem?
I finally get it now.
How unbelievably embarrassing.
Sadako, you should be
more confident in yourself.
D'ya know what I mean?
So, c'mon, you've already drawn the eye
of the two hottest guys
in this whole school.
Me and Kazehaya.
Oh wow!
So then, you and Kazehaya really are
the two hottest guys in the entire school?
Well, yeah. Probably.
He just said something mind-blowing to me.
When I first talked about
how you should date me,
I wasn't kidding around.
You may not actually remember it,
but hey, you had a lot going on then.
And, at the time, I just didn't understand
a thing about you.
I'm sorry for all that.
But, it's true that I was intrigued enough
to keep an eye on you.
I simply can't help watching people
I'm fascinated with.
He's looking straight-ahead.
- Hey, I...
- Uh?
I feel... like I've learned
so much about life.
All because of you.
Mmm, I feel the same.
You made me realize things
that weren't even on my radar before.
Oo.
Like, "Out of the mouth comes evil."
And how incredibly cute Ayane can be.
I just wanted to get all that
off my chest, ya know?
Yeah, that's much better.
Well, gonna see
if I can catch up with Ayane.
Huh. Huh?
Huh?!
See you later! Good luck!
Hmm. Chizu still isn't replying
to my messages.
- Ayane! Hey!
- Hmm?
I found you!
Where's Sawako?
She was headed back
to the classroom, I think.
You better not have spouted
a bunch of weird stuff at her again.
You sure don't trust me, do ya?
Just stop worrying, okay?
- So what did you talk about?
- Hmm?
I gave her some advice with Kazehaya...
You for real?!
Stop interfering! I mean it!
Leave 'em alone!
Uh! What? What's funny?
Well, actually,
you always seem to be worrying
about other people, Ayane.
Mmm? That couldn't be further
from the truth.
- 'Cause I'm always putting myself first.
- Really?
You seem like a real people pleaser
from my perspective.
People pleaser?
- Are you for real?!
- Yeah.
You should try saying that
to any of our classmates.
I mean, if you really wanna laugh.
Uh, I will. Sure.
Oh, knock it off.
They're gonna laugh at you.
What's your deal?
Don't you think you're giving me
way too much credit?
No, I'm not. I'm sure.
But it is strange to me.
You're incredibly smart,
and you can read the room.
And I'm convinced
you could handle anything.
So why do you always have
such a low opinion of yourself?
Like, you don't know me.
No one really does.
I'm not that person.
That's not true though.
It's fine. Enough sweet talk.
I'm just not that girl.
That's really not true.
If I were a guy instead,
I think I'd choose
to go out with Chizu or Sawako.
Um, maybe Kurumi.
I bet I could do
a way better job than Kazehaya is.
Hey, Ayane...
Earlier, I told you that
I'd never fallen in love first, right?
But... honestly,
I don't think any of the guys I dated
were that into me at any point either.
But, well,
since I am the way I am,
I guess that's just a given.
It's mutual, right?
So, either way, I'd still like to at least
have someone to lean on when I'm lonely.
But you're wrong about that.
Hey, it's fine.
Oh, Miura. For you.
Hmm?
- Makin' some memories?
- We're not!
See ya!
Hey. Go put this
on the bulletin board, will ya?
Wait! I'm talkin' to you, blondie!
She's actually super awkward, huh?
Huh? No way!
She knows what she's doin'.
It's finally over!
Let's go home!
I still haven't gotten a reply, but...
If she's asleep,
let's leave her a snack and go home.
Yeah. Oh... Oh, uh, Kazehaya,
I'm going with Ayane to Chizu's.
To Yoshida's house? Huh.
I wonder if she's even at home?
- Is there something wrong?
- D-- don't worry about it. It's nothing.
Everything's fine.
- Sawako? Let's go.
- Uh, mm-hmm. Bye.
I'm really hungry.
I just couldn't figure out
a good way to reply.
Sorry, Yano-chin, Sawako.
I've been thinking.
Like, a lot.
But I can't wrap my head around this.
I see.
At times like these, the one I'd talk to,
it was always Ryu.
Here. Rice balls.
You're hungry, aren't ya?
Wha-- Kazehaya! H-- how'd you...
What do you mean? Obviously, Ryu told me.
I think she's probably around here.
Sorry, Shota, but could you
bring this to her for me?
I'm sure she's gotten...
really hungry by now.
- Better eat.
- Fine, I will!
What are you all calm
and chill for though, huh?
Seriously though.
You're livin' the sweet life
without a care in the world,
gettin' to be all lovey-dovey
with Sawako forever!
These are so good!
Right, right. Thank you!
Damn it!
When the time comes and I'm reborn,
I'm gonna be you, Kazehaya!
Huh? But why?
'Cause if I could become you...
What?
It's nothing.
Ryu and I could keep being best friends.
So, why did you turn him down?
Yeah. Everyone asks me the same thing.
Dating him?
That would be
the more natural thing to do?
But, in that moment...
Since that person
was always you.
When it sunk in, and I realized
he meant he liked me in that way,
I figured that
I should tell him how I felt.
I've never
thought of you like that.
In the most
honest way possible.
Maybe the relationship we had
only worked the way it did because of Ryu
and his feelings for me.
But, wouldn't that mean
everything I'd held dear till then
never actually existed in the first place?
Didn't that
make you happy though?
Even a little bit?
I never even thought about it.
Hey, Kazehaya, did you know
that Ryu felt like that about me?
No. We almost never talk about
that kind of thing.
I figured though.
He's always being misunderstood, right?
By everyone.
But, regardless, it was always obvious
how much he cared about you.
No matter what
those specific feelings were.
It's the exact same for me.
I get it.
Ryu's my best friend
and, like, I'm his older sister.
In other words,
I've thought of him as my younger brother.
Or maybe he's my older brother,
and I'm his younger sister?
Whatever, I don't know.
It honestly didn't matter at all
which way it was.
- Chizu!
- Huh?
Yano-chin. Sawako.
Right. That's my cue.
Thank you, Kazehaya.
Hey, uh, what's going on, you two?
There's no fever.
We're the ones who wanted to know
what's going on with you.
Kazehaya texted us a little bit ago
to tell us that you were here
on the wharf.
You have a cold, don't you?
You shouldn't be out here
where it's freezing.
Huh? What do you mean?
I don't have a cold.
Uh, I skipped because, uh...
...I didn't want to face Ryu.
Uh, what?
Did something else happen between you two?
No.
But, just yesterday,
you were both so normal.
No, they weren't.
- Not at all!
- Huh?
Because when you weren't wanting to see
or even hang out with Sanada,
I knew that something wasn't right.
Just because it's special
doesn't mean it's magically okay.
I thought... it could still be the same.
You know?
But I was wrong. It can't!
Now... can't go and eat ramen!
We can't play games together anymore!
No more inside jokes
or New Year's shrine visits!
We're not siblings anymore!
It hurts
because he's so important to you.
Chizu, those feelings you just
poured out to us,
does Ryu know?
I'm sure he's picked up on them.
Has he?
Does he know everything about you?
And do you know everything about him?
Of course I've realized it.
How he keeps getting bigger than me.
That he's way taller than me now.
I guess I can see...
there are things I don't know about him.
A lot of things.
Hey! What are you doing?!
I can't believe you two right now!
Oh, you're going to get it!
Goat?
We're gonna get it! We're gonna get it!
Ugh!
I can't believe you did that,
you little...
Someone's in trouble! Here. Rice balls.
Ohhhh!
Eat a lot, okay?
- I love rice balls!
- Uh-huh!
Rice balls are Ryu's
favorite food too, you know.
I'm so sorry about the floor, Tetsu.
Please allow me to pay for it.
Huh? Nah, it's fine!
I mean, if she marries
into our family one day...
Chizu, this will be your home.
So, sound good?
You'd be able to have a lot of rice balls.
- Mmm!
- Eat 'em at home!
Hey! I'm home!
- Oh, Chi, you're here.
- Toru!
Ryu, whoa, are you still eating those?
Here we go. Okay, say cheese!
Cheese!
- Look how much they've grown up.
- Isn't that great?
- You're both in the same class.
- Uh-huh.
You better not
break anything in the classroom!
M'kay!
- Uh-oh.
- Hey! Who did that?!
Run!
Have fun, but remember, think of others!
Argh! Arrrgh! Argh!
That girl is such a troublemaker.
For real.
I think her energy
is her greatest quality.
- How's Ryu doing?
- Hmm? I think he's good.
- Oh, hi, I'm home.
- Ryu! How was school today?
It was fun.
I made some rice balls.
That boy's so laid-back.
And he doesn't have a lot to say.
So people tend to misunderstand
how he's feeling.
It's impossible for anyone to
really know what Ryu's thinking, ya know?
- Huh?
- And he's a little scary too.
Yeah, and he glares a lot.
Hey, that's not true at all!
Hey, Chizu. You causing trouble again?
But they got it all wrong.
Now, it's time to have our lunch together.
Okay!
Look at what mine has!
Wow! It looks so yummy, Micchan!
Oh no! I'm sorry, Ryu!
Lookit! I brought a banana!
Oy! I stepped on something.
A-- a rice ball? How?
R-- Ryu, I'm sorry!
Oh, i-- it's yours?
I'm sorry.
R-- Ryu...
Huh?
Uh, what happened?
Ryu got really mad at me!
- I said I was sorry, but he won't listen.
- Not true!
It's just that he really loves rice balls,
so it made him real sad.
When you apologized,
he wasn't able to hear you.
He's not mad at all!
They don't get it.
Ryu's not scary at all.
Here. Have my sushi.
Huh? He's happy.
Thanks.
Maybe he's too nice.
He should get mad more.
But I get it.
I see.
But, hey, isn't it great that Ryu
has you to understand that about him?
I'm so glad.
Whoa! It's awesome!
Mm-hmm.
- What did you write for your wish?
- Please help me get real good at baseball.
- And you?
- Huh? I'm not telling you!
If I say it, then it won't come true.
- Oh, Toru!
- Welcome home!
Oh, hi, Chi.
What did you write on your tanzaku?
He-he-he-he! It's secret!
Toru! Come play with me! Pretty please?!
Please? Please? Please? Please?!
He's amazing, you know? Toru, I mean.
'Cause when we get buns,
he splits the pork and red bean in half!
- Uh?
- C'mon, how can you not get it?
It's totally smart.
That way you get two different buns.
A two for one.
It's a really good deal, ya know?
How is that good?
So, here, you buy a red-bean bun,
and then I'll buy a pork bun.
I wanna get a rice ball.
That's dumb!
Your mom's rice balls are the best ones
in the whole entire world!
You can eat them at home!
To... ru.
Wait, Ryu!
- The pork bun.
- No, it's fine.
But that's how you eat 'em.
You both share the halves.
It's fine!
When he held her hand,
it was different than when he holds mine!
We didn't end up getting home that day
until after it got dark outside.
So, yeah, you can guess
how much trouble we both got into.
But, Ryu gripped my hand
really hard, so hard,
and he just kept walking
and walking forever.
Well, go ahead
and have these for now.
I got really hungry,
and my tears dried up.
After that,
there was no need to cry anymore.
Ryu! Let's go to school!
Wow! Gosh! Chizu!
I wish I could drive you to school,
but my husband needed the car today.
- See ya later.
- You be careful, okay?
Okay, bye.
Uh, hold on, Chizu.
Hmm. Perfect.
I can't breathe.
Great. That means it's tight enough.
Don't get blown away by the wind!
- 'Kay!
Hold hands! And don't let go, okay?
There'll be rice balls for you
when you get home!
- Okay!
That was...
the last time I ever saw Auntie.
She was on her way
to pick up her youngest, her car slipped,
and she crashed into a pole!
It was such
a terrible snowstorm.
I'm sure she couldn't see a thing.
It took so long
for them to find her.
The poor woman.
And she was still so young.
Chizu, go on.
Tetsu!
Tetsuko, Chiaki's here to see you.
Big brother took it!
Hey, stop it!
Wow!
Uh, yeah, but they...
I promise
they don't mean any harm.
Chizu... come here.
The sadness
might feel like too much now,
but things will slowly feel normal again.
That's the way grief tends to work.
Tell Auntie Tetsu,
thank you for everything!
That pain
may not go away completely,
but it will fade over time.
Here you go, Chizu.
You must be hungry. Go ahead and eat.
If you find yourself
getting hungry...
- How is it?
- Good.
I'm glad.
...and pain lets up for just a moment
and you smile,
there's nothing wrong with that, okay?
But... Ryu.
Ryu...
Hey, Ryu! I'm here!
- Mm.
- Oh, Chizu.
Thanks for always coming to fetch him.
Morning, Uncle!
Hey! Wait a sec.
You two be careful, 'kay?
Oh, Uncle!
Tonight, Toru and Ryu
can come have dinner at our place, 'kay?
Sorry for any inconvenience.
Hope you have fun
making your delicious ramen!
I will.
Uh, hey!
Ryu, if you ever have a problem,
come talk to me anytime.
Mmm. I'm okay.
- Poor Ryu. How terrible.
- Yeah.
But, at least he seems the same as usual?
Ryu hasn't cried yet.
- Go on. You boys too. Please!
- And eat your fill, okay?
Ryu,
you can have seconds if you'd like.
Yes, please.
He also never smiles.
What? Why are you so mad, Chizu?
I'm not mad, okay?!
Ryu?
- What's up? You haven't gone to sleep yet?
- Uh-uh. Gotta pee.
Toru?
You're up? The bathroom?
No. I just can't seem to fall asleep.
- Should I turn on the light?
- Nah.
My eyes are used to the dark now.
It would be too much.
You sure do look like Tetsu.
I'm missing her like crazy.
It was all so sudden.
Yeah.
Hey, uh, where are Toru and Ryu today?
Ryu told me he was invited
to eat dinner at his coach's house.
Oh, so he's over there.
I know Toru's got a new girlfriend now,
so I think he's with her.
Ah, does he now? Sounds like him.
Should have expected, huh?
Hey, your girlfriend
hasn't been around lately.
- Did something happen?
- Just leave me alone!
What are you doing, Chizu?
- Want rice balls? I'll make some.
- I'm... fine!
Thank you, dinner was great.
Course. Take care.
Here. Don't forget this.
Appreciated.
Ryu?
- Did you just get home?
- Uh, mm-hmm.
Oh, uh, what's that?
Oh, that's right.
- It's probably meant for you.
- Hmm.
From Chi, huh?
How about we share it
for breakfast tomorrow, 'kay?
But... Shota's family already gave me
something to eat for breakfast tomorrow.
So you should eat that all yourself.
Snow.
It hurts.
Yeah.
Hey, it's just you tonight, Ryu?
Toru told me
he's eating at his girlfriend's again.
Looks good! I'm diggin' in!
SANADA
All right.
Did you get enough to eat, Ryu?
Mm-hmm. Thanks for the meal.
Mm?
Huh?
Huh...
It's for...
you, Ryu.
Oh.
The truth is,
we just couldn't accept it.
It's so strange.
T-- Toru!
Chi... Hey, it's not like we're never gonna
see each other again.
I'll come back to visit you guys, okay?
Mmm. Mmm. Okay, you promise?
Sometimes,
people leave even when they're alive.
Ryu... look after Dad.
I'm counting on you.
And you can't be
with people who are dead.
Both situations leave an empty space...
...but they're totally different.
Even if you end up
never seeing someone again,
simply knowing they're alive
somewhere is enough.
- Toru's gone. Really.
- Mmm.
You know what?
- I'll be your sibling now.
- Wha--
I'm not kidding. I promise.
Chi, take care of Ryu for me, all right?
But... you've got me, Ryu.
Always.
A sibling who's the same age
by your side forever.
So I'm the big brother?
Oh, yeah. Huh?
How come?!
But my birthday comes before yours!
Just a feeling.
Forever... and ever.
Always.
So, yeah, all of this sucks.
I can't make sense of it,
and I don't have a real answer.
But what I do know
is that I need to tell Ryu about
all these mixed-up feelings right now.
We lost someone, and time went on.
Our feelings grew numb,
and we let ourselves forget.
As we move on to a future where
we can smile as if nothing ever happened.
Is that what Ryu... what I... really want?
Today, I didn't bring sushi rolls.
These are my rice balls.
These two are your favorites.
The egg and mayo, and bonito flakes.
That one is salted rice. And pickled plum.
Enjoy.
It's early, but that's
your birthday present.
This year, I tried but... I couldn't
find anything I thought you'd like.
But... you did.
Wh-- why are... you staring?
Don't look at me! Stop!
We haven't been alone together since...
It's embarrassing.
Why did... you have to tell me
that you liked me?!
Once you say it out loud, it's all over!
What we both had together, it's gone!
To me, it was precious!
More than anything else!
Now, it's all gone!
'Cause... whenever I see you now,
I have this strange new thought
cross my mind.
Does this guy really love me
or something--
Believe it, then!
Believe it.
That day, there was no reason
to hold back how I felt.
'Cause I wanted it to end.
So let's end it!
So that this can finally start.
It's December.
The city of Kitahoro
is now covered in snow.
Morning! It's freezing, huh?
Gah!
- Ouch!
- Oh, sorry.
- Huh? Whoa!
- Huh?
- When'd you get here?!
- What do you mean?
Hey, about the other day.
The thing.
- Hmm?
- You know what I mean, that!
So... yeah, thank you.
Have things calmed down now?
Actually, it's worse.
- Really? Glad to hear it.
- What the hell?!
So, anyway, as a small token
of my gratitude,
if you ever have anything troubling you,
I'll lend you an ear.
Wait. You, Yoshida?
Well, yeah! I can totally keep a... uh...
Can't say it, can you, huh?
It's hard to talk about it anyway.
Well, I'm planning on
finding the right time myself.
Huh? So there is something?
Hey.
It seems like Chizu's always
got something on her mind these days.
Probably about Sanada.
Huh? That's what he said to you?!
Okay, so what did you do after that?
He ate rice balls. That's it.
Huh? Why rice balls?
Because I brought them over to him.
Since they're his favorite food.
He seemed like
a whole different person to me.
Chizu looked...
so cute and girly just now.
Oh, Chizu.
When it comes to Ryu,
she always gets so upset.
Even if it's over something stupid
no one else would get mad about.
You think that she's even aware of it?
I, uh... I wonder.
Well.
That face tells me she has no clue.
Look at that mouth.
We could just toss in a snack,
and she wouldn't notice.
Uh, no, she could choke!
Oh, don't worry about it.
- Argh!
- I'm awake, okay?!
Sorry. You didn't seem as doom and gloom
as you've been lately.
I thought it'd be fine.
Oh!
Thank goodness! She's feeling better!
So library after school today?
Yes.
Shall we start
with the more general stuff?
- Sure.
- Huh. Wow. Lucky.
A library date?
We're studying for exams!
Exams?
You say some weird things.
- Finals. She means our finals.
- I'll see you later, then, all right?
Yeah.
That's right!
You'll be celebrating Christmas
with Kazehaya this year, huh?
No, I-- I mean,
we haven't talked about it!
Please, there's no way
that's not gonna happen.
You're totally going to spend it together.
It goes without saying.
You have to make up for last year.
I forgot!
I wanna go.
I don't wanna miss out on Christmas.
Then, it's time!
Whatever it takes,
you need to convince your dad!
Because, this year, the two of you...
are boyfriend and girlfriend!
I... I wonder.
It's not like
we've even talked about it at all yet.
But is... is that just something
that couples are expected to do?
I don't know.
Honestly, if I go based on
how things seem between us lately,
it doesn't feel like
we'll be celebrating together.
Sadako, you should be
more confident in yourself.
You're already close.
I think you're right next to each other.
Hmm.
Now that I am this close to him,
I shouldn't be thinking like that anymore.
This year,
we're boyfriend and girlfriend, huh?
Sawako!
Listen up. Your old man has given
a lot of thought to Christmas this year.
Huh?
Then, it's time. Whatever it takes,
you need to convince your dad!
Oh, uh, Dad, I...
This year, you can celebrate Christmas
with everyone. How's that sound?
What do you mean by everyone?
She's with Kazehaya,
so don't you think they should--
Everyone!
I mean like Ayane, Chizu, and...
I'm saying you can go, okay?
You mean it?
Thank you, Dad! Thank you!
We can celebrate as a family
on the 23rd or 25th this year.
Wow, dear, what a big step!
I'm so happy!
That's all I can think!
Because the painful
unrequited feelings from last year
will be mutual this time around.
Lately, I've been thinking
so much about how we are.
About how a boyfriend
and girlfriend should be.
But that's not what's important.
What I want
is to be together with Kazehaya.
Not just to gauge
how he's feeling about us,
but because spending time with him
is what really matters.
When exams are over,
I'll ask Kazehaya
to spend Christmas with me.
- We're done!
- I'm gonna sleep!
Time to party!
Let's get some pork buns
on our way home.
It's over!
- Sawako!
- Uh!
- What are your plans?
- I have to... fulfill the mission before me!
- Yeah! Go get it, girl!
- Right! I'm outta here!
It's over!
This is the moment I've been waiting for!
I'm going to tell him!
Ka-- Kazehaya!
Wanna walk together?
Uh...
Okay. Sure.
- Oh, um, Kazehaya--
- Kuronuma.
Yes?
Listen. Do you... have Christmas plans?
You know what?
This year, I don't have to stay
with my folks.
I already had a talk
with my mom and dad, so...
- So I...
- Great!
It's official. Christmas together.
All of us.
I'll be with Kazehaya for Christmas!
Wait.
With everyone?